Processed by 繁化姬 dict-c2c8d0e1-r866 @ 2019/06/18 22:29:49 | https://zhconvert.org
哈登菲爾德鎮，伊利諾斯州
黑貓，小妖，帚柄和幽靈
Black cats and goblins and broomsticks and ghosts.
哈登菲爾德鎮，伊利諾斯州
巫婆的南瓜放那烘烤著
Pumpkins of witches are there to roast.
哈登菲爾德鎮，伊利諾斯州
巫婆的南瓜放那烘烤著
Pumpkins of witches are there to roast.
萬聖節之夜
1963年
巫婆的南瓜放那烘烤著
Pumpkins of witches are there to roast.
你可能認為，他們在嚇我 也許是吧
ou may think, they scare me. You're probably right.
萬聖節之夜
1963年
萬聖夜裡的黑貓和小妖
Black cats and goblins on Halloween night.
萬聖節之夜
1963年
萬聖夜裡的黑貓和小妖
Black cats and goblins on Halloween night.
不給糖就搗亂！！！
Trick-or-treat!!!
我爸爸媽媽10點後才回來 是嗎？
My parents won't be home untill ten.  Are you sure?
沒有其他人在吧？
We're all alone, aren't we?
麥克不知去那裡了
Michael's around someplace ...
把那東西拿開
Take off that thing.
我們上樓去 好
Let's go upstairs. Ok.
朱迪絲，很晚了，我要走了
Look, Judith, it's very late.
I gotta go.
你明天會打電話給我吧？
Will you call me tomorrow?
好，一定 你保證？
Yeah, sure. Promise?
保證
Yeah.
麥克？
Michael?
史密斯森林，伊利諾斯州
10月30日，1978年
你以前有沒有處理過這種事？
Ever done anything like this before?
只有在安全限度之內
Only minimum security.
了解了
I see.
入口在右邊幾百碼處
The driveway's a few hundred yards up on the right.
我唯一擔心的是他們激動的時候
The only thing that ever bothers me is their jibberish.
會不停的發出各種奇怪的聲言
When they start raving on and on ...
不必擔心這個
You haven't anything to worry about.
他已經有15年沒說過話了
He hasn't spoken a word in 15 years.
有沒有要特別注意的事？
Are there any special instructions?
只要清楚我們是在處理什麼事就好
Just try to understand what we're dealing with here.
不要掉以輕心
Don't underestimate it.
你不認為我們和他一樣也正在期待著這件事？
Don't you think we could refer to 'it' as him?
你要這樣說也可以
If you say so.
你的同情心在作祟，大夫
Your compassion's overwhelming, Doctor.
在帶他去見法官之前，我還為他做點什麼？
What do I give him,
when we're taking him in front of the judge?
想法奇怪
Thorazin.
這樣根本解決不了問題
我也是這麼認為
Barely be able to sit up.
That's the idea.
你這次很認真，是不是？
You're serious about that, aren't you?
是的
Yeah.
你是說你實在不希望放他出來
不希望
You mean, you actually never want him to get out.
Never ever ...
絕不希望
Never.
那為什麼我們還要帶他去哈地郡？
因為法律這樣規定
Then why we're taking up to Hardy county,if he just gonna ...
Because that is the law.
到了
We are.
他們什麼時候開始可以四處閒逛的？
Since when do they let them wander around?
到大門去 - 我們不是應該去 - 快走
Pull up to the main gate.
Shouldn't we ...  Pull up?
停車
Stop here.
我們不是應該直接去醫院的嗎？
在這裡等著
Shouldn't we go on up to the hospital on ...
Wait!
你沒事吧？
Are you all right?
你沒事吧？- 我沒事 - 他跑了
You all right?
- Yes, I'm ok. - He's gone. He's gone?
這混蛋跑了
The evil is gone!
我得趕緊
I gotta ...
海德非斯，伊利諾州
萬聖節
別忘了拿鎖匙去麥爾家
Don't forget to drop the key off the Myers place ...
好的
I won't.
他們會在10點半來看房子把它放在門口被子下面
我會的
They're coming by look at the house at 10:30.Be sure you leave it under the mat ...
Promise.
勞莉
Laurie ...
嗨，湯米
Hi Tommy.
今晚你來嗎？
同一時間，同一地點
Coming over tonight?
Same time, same place.
我們能做傑克燈籠嗎？
當然可以
Can we make Jack-O-Lanterns?
Sure.
然後看恐怖電影？
對
And watch the monster movies?
- Sure.
你會念書給我聽嗎？
Will you read to me?
能做爆米花嗎？
當然，當然，當然
Can we make popcorn?
- Sure, sure, sure.
你最好走快點
You better hurry up.
你怎麼走這條路上學？
我爸爸叫我走的
How can you walk in the school this way?
My dad asked me to.
為什麼？
Why?
我要留鎖匙
I have to drop off the key.
為什麼？
Why?
因為他要賣房子
Because he's gonna sell a house.
為什麼？
Why?
因為那是他的工作
哪套房子？
Because that's his job.
Where?
麥爾家的房子
The Meyers house.
麥爾家的房子！
The Meyers house!
你最好不要到那裡去
You're not supposed to go up there?
不，我要去
Yes, I am.
那是鬼屋
That's a spook house.
看著吧！
Just watch.
郎尼從來不敢進去
Lonnie Elam said never to go up there.
郎尼說那是鬼屋
Lonnie Elam said that's a haunted house.
他說那裡面發生過恐怖的事
- 郎尼大概升不到六年級
He said real awful stuff happened there once.
- Lonnie Elam probably won't get out of the sixth grade.
我必須走了
I gotta go.
晚上見
I see you tonight.
再見！再見！
Bye.  Bye.
* 多希望能一直陪伴著你 *
* I wish I had you all alone ... *
* 只有我們兩人 *
* Just the two of us ... *
* 我會擁你入懷 *
* I would hold you close to me ... *
* 緊緊擁抱著 *
* So close to me ... *
* 只有我們兩人 *
* Just the two ... *
這不是我的責任，山姆
噢，不
I'm not responsible, Sam. - Oh, no ...
我跟他們說過他有多危險
I told them how dangerous he was!
你應該設置路障 那小圍壁連5歲小孩都阻止不了
You wouldn't have enough two roadblocks
and an all-points bulletin wouldn't stop a five-year-old!
但他是你的病人，大夫
如果他很強壯，你應該告訴大家
But he was your patient, Doctor. If precautions
weren't strong enough, you should have told somebody.
我跟每個人都說過了！
I told everybody!
但沒人聽我的話
那我就無能為力了
Nobody listened.
- There's nothing else I can do.
你最好回去再打個電話
You can get back in there
and get back on the telephone.
告訴他們昨晚什麼人逃走了
Tell them exactly
who walked out of here last night ...
告訴他們他會逃到哪裡
也許只是逃走而己
And tell them exactly where he is going.
- Probably going.
我好像在浪費口舌
山姆，他家離這裡150里
I'm wasting my time. - Sam, Haddonfield is
a hundred and fifty miles away from here.
而且，老實說，他不會開車
他昨晚開得相當好！
Now, now for God's sake, he can't drive a car!
- He was doing very well last night!
一定是這裡的人教他的
Maybe someone around here gave him lessons.
到了這裡這本書就結束了
... and the book ends.
但其實撒母耳要說的是
But what Samuels is really talking about here ...
命運
is fate.
各位知道
You see ...
書裡命運跟很多人都有關
fate caught up with several lives here.
不論科林斯採取什麼樣的行動
No matter what course of action Collins took ...
他都擺脫不了命運的束縛
he was destined to his own fate,
每一天都是命運的安排
his own day of reckoning with himself.
這
The idea ...
就像
is ...
天命
that destiny ...
是非常真實的，具體的東西
我們每個人都得處理好
is a very real, concrete thing
that every person has to deal with.
對於命運，撒母耳和卡斯提的觀點有什麼不同？勞莉？
How does Samuels' view of fate differ from that of Costaine's? Laurie?
叫我嗎？
M'am?
回答問題
Answer the question.
卡斯提寫到命運某些程度上跟信仰有關
Costaine wrote that fate was somehow related only to religion
而撒母耳認為那只是一種自然物
就像泥土，空氣，火和水一樣
or where Samuels felt that ... well, fate was like
a natural element, like earth, air, fire, and water.
對，撒母耳把命運人格化了
That's right, Samuels definitely personified fate.
撒母耳寫到，命運是不可移動的，就像一座山
In Samuels' writing, fate is a moveable like a mountain.
對人來說是無法改變的
It stands, where man passes a way.
命運永遠不會改變
Fate never changes.
你，抱南瓜的 你們走開！
You, with pumpkin. Leave me alone!
他會捉到你的！捉到你的，捉到你的
He's gonna get you!
- He's gonna get you, he's gonna get you...
惡魔人來了！快走開！
The boogeyman is coming! Leave me alone!
他大概不膽小
你知不知道萬聖節是什麼節日？
He doesn't believe us.
- Don't you know what happens on Halloween?
知道，有糖果吃
Yeah, we get candy.
惡魔人來了！惡魔人來了！惡魔人來了！
The boogey man!
- The boogey man, the boogey man, the boogey ...
他已經動身了
He's on his way.
你一定要相信我，警官 他要來哈登菲爾德鎮
You gotta believe me officer,he is coming to Haddonfield.
因為我了解他
Because I know him.
我是他的醫生 你一定要有所準備
I'm his doctor. You must be ready for him.
不信的話，那就準備棺材吧
If you don't, it's your funeral.
* 我們來自哈登菲爾德鎮，我們很自豪 *
We're from Haddonfield, couldn't be prouder.
* 聽不清楚嗎，那我們再大聲點 *
Can't hear now, we yell a little louder.
* 我們來自哈登菲爾德鎮，我們很自豪 *
We're from Haddonfield, couldn't be prouder!
* 聽不清楚嗎，那我們再大聲點 *
噢，看看你
Can't hear now ... continue
- Oh, look at you.
快把那些書扔掉 你應該去購物
Get off the books you have.
You neeed a shopping cart to get home.
* 嘿，哈登菲爾德鎮！*
Heeey Haddonfield!
- Yeah, one for me.
這真是趕死人了！早上有三個新的口號要學
You know it's totally insane! We have three new cheers to learn in the morning,
下午有球賽，5點要去做頭髮，然後8點去跳舞
the game in the afternoon, I have to get my hairdone at five and the dance is at eight.
我的時間都被用光了！
I'll be totally wiped out!
明天再做估計來不及
完全來不及
I don't think get enough to do tommorow.
Totally!
跟以前一樣，我似乎沒事做
這是你自己的錯，我不必同情你
As usual, I have nothing to do.
- It's your own fault and I don't feel bit sorry for you.
嘿，琳達，勞莉
Hey, Lynda, Laurie!
怎麼沒等我？
Why didn't you wait for me?
我們等了呀！
We did.
等了15分鐘 你根本沒出現
胡說！我這不是來了嗎？
Fifteen minutes. You totally never showed.
- That's not true. Here I am.
怎麼了，安妮？你臉上沒笑容
我永遠不會再笑了
What's wrong, Annie? You're not smiling.
- I'm never smiling again.
保羅帶我去男更衣室，然後開發神秘領域？
已經被完全開發過了
Paul dragged me into the boys' locker room to tell ...
- Exploring uncharted territory?- It's been totally charted.
我們只是聊天
We just talked.
當然，當然
Sure, sure.
他因往窗戶扔雞蛋被人逮住了
然後他父母就不讓他出門了
Old jerko got caught throwing eggs
and soaping windows. His parents grounded him.
他今晚來不了了
He can't come over tonight.
你今晚不是要去當保姆嗎？她當保姆的唯一原因就是為了有個地方
噢，糟了
I thought you were babysitting tonight. The only reason she babysits is to have a place to...
Oh shit ...
我已經有地方了
I have a place for that.
我忘了化學課本
I forgot my chemistry book.
有什麼關係？我常忘了拿化學課本，數學課本，英語課本
So, who cares? I always forget my chemistry book
and my math book and my english book and my ...
有時候法語課本
and let's see my French book and ...
其實沒有書也沒關係 我根本不需要這些書
我真希望把這些書都丟掉
Who needs books anyway? I don't need books.
I always forget all of my books. I mean ...
有沒有帶書回去根本不要緊
it doesn't really matter if I you got that books or not.
那不是范格拉漢姆嗎？
Hey, isn't that the van Graham?
我想不是
I don't think so.
他長得很帥
I think he's cute.
嘿，怪人！
Hey, jerk ...
馬路殺手！
Speed kills!
糟了，他不能開玩笑？
Gosh ... Can't he take a joke?
安妮，你總有一天會給我們惹禍的
You know, Annie, some day
you gonna get us all into deep trouble.
真的
Totally.
我不喜歡沒有幽默感的人
I hate a guy with a car and no sense of humor.
今晚我們還是照舊？
Well, are we still on for tonight?
我不想給你惹麻煩，琳達
I wouldn't want to get you in deep trouble, Lynda.
別這樣，安妮
Oh come on, Annie ...
巴伯和我已經計劃了一個星期了
Bob and I've been planning on it all week.
好吧！
All right.
華萊士夫婦七點離開家
The Wallaces leave at seven.
我要去道爾家當保姆
I'm babysitting the Doyles.
只隔了三套房子遠，我們可以一起玩了
太好了，我有三樣選擇
It's only three houses down. We can keep each other
company. - Ohh, terrific ... I've got three choices.
照顧小孩睡覺，和琳達鬼混，還有跟你聊天
Watch the kid sleep, listen to Lynda
screw around or talk to you.
我們真
We're so ma ...
這裡
Here.
晚上什麼時候？
What time at night?
還不知道 我必須把我的小弟弄走然後和和巴伯一起！
I don't know yet. I have to get out of taking my little
brother trick- or-treating. - Saving the treats for Bob?
真幽默！
Fun-ny.
再見！
再見！- 再見！
See you.
- Bye. - Bye.
安妮，看
Annie, look.
看什麼？
Look where?
樹林後面
Behind the bush.
我沒看到東西
那個剛才開車的，被你吼的那個
I don't see anything.
- That guy who drove by so fast, when you yelled at.
他很敏感，是不是？
Subtle, isn't he?
嘿，混蛋！
Hey, creep!
勞莉，親愛的，他想和你說話
Laurie, dear, he wants to talk to you.
他晚上想和你約會
He wants to take you out tonight.
他剛才站在這裡
He was standing right there.
可憐的勞莉
Poor Laurie.
你又失去了一個機會
Scared another one away.
真可悲，你永遠無法和男孩約會
It's tragic. You never go out.
你不應該整天幫別人看孩子
別人覺得我聰明
You must have a small fortune stashed from babysitting
so much. - Guys think I'm too smart.
我認為你太怪異了 竟然在樹叢後看到一個人
I don't. I think you're whacko.Now you're seeing men behind bushes.
溫暖的家到了
Well, home sweet home.
待會見
See you later.
再見
Bye.
對不起，勞莉
布萊克先生，對不起  我不是有意嚇你的
Excuse me, Laurie. - Oh, Mr. Brackett,
I'm sorry, Mr. Brackett. - Oh, I didn't mean to scary ya.
對不起
I'm sorry.
今天是萬聖節 我想每個人都預期會被嚇一嚇
You know, it's Halloween.
I guess everybody's entitled to a one good scare.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
很高興見到你，先生
Nice evening, sir.
不給糖就搗亂 不給糖就搗亂
Trick -o - treat, Trick -o - treat.
小孩子
Oh, kiddo ...
都是在迷信中長大的
thought you grew up from superstition.
哈囉？
Hello?
到底是誰？
Who is this?
哈囉？
Hello?
為什麼掛斷電話？
Why did you hang up on me?
安妮？
Annie?
剛才是你嗎？
Was that you?
是呀！
怎麼不說話，嚇死我了
Of course.
- Why didn't you say anything? You scared me to death.
我嘴裡塞滿了吃的 你聽到了嗎？
had my mouth full. Couldn't you hear me?
我以為是恐嚇電話
I thought it was an obscene phone call.
你聽到我只是在吃東西，抱歉
我沒聽清楚
Now you hear obscene chewing. You're losing it, Laurie.
- I've already lost it.
我懷疑
I Doubt that.
聽好了，我媽要借車給我，我六點半來接你
Listen, my mother is letting me use her car.
I'll pick you up. 6:30.
好，再見！
再見！
Ok, bye.
-Bye.
冷靜
Just calm down.
真荒謬
This is ridiculous.
快進來
Hurry up.
還有點時間
Just have time.
朱迪絲麥爾 麥爾
Judith Myers. Myers.
第18排第20個
Row 18 ... plot 20.
你可知道這種事經常發生
Hey, you know. You know,
every town has something like this happen.
我記得在羅素維爾鎮
I remember over in Russellville.
查理包爾 大概在15年前
Old Charly Bowles. About fifteen years ago.
有一天晚上他吃完晚餐
One night he, he finished dinner ...
離開餐桌
And he excused himself from the table ...
到停車庫
And he went out to the garage ...
拿了一把斧頭
He got himself a hack saw ...
回到房裡
And then he went back into the house ...
和他的太太和二個孩子吻別
And he kissed his wife and two children goodbye ...
然後就 到了嗎？
And then he proceeded ...
- Where are we?
在這裡
It's right over here.
麥爾，朱迪絲麥爾，我記得她
Myers, Judith Myers. I remember her.
簡直無法相信
Couldn't believe.
這麼小的男孩
Such a young boy.
迷路了嗎？
Well, you lost?
他們為什麼這麼做？
Why do they do it?
這些小鬼
Goddamn kids.
在萬聖節他們什麼事都幹得出來
They'll do anything for Halloweens.
這是墓碑
噢，我知道
It was grave, hers.
- Oh, I know that.
18，19
18, 19 ...
朱迪絲麥爾的
Judith Myers.
他回來了
He came home.
你還在幻想嗎？
You still spooked?
我沒有幻想
I wasn't spooked.
你胡說
我沒有
Lies.
- I wasn't.
我看到有人在李德先生的後院
可能是李德先生本人吧！
Saw somebody standing in Mr. Riddle's back yard.
- Probably Mr. Riddle.
他在看著我
李德先生看著你？勞莉，李德先生已經87歲了
He was watching me.
- Mr. Riddle was watching you? Laurie, Mr. Riddle is 87.
他還是可以看的呀！
He can still watch.
可能他所能做的只是看看而己
That's probably all he can do.
這南瓜是用來做什麼的？
幫湯米帶的 他大概要做個傑克燈籠 這能讓他忙一陣子
What's the pumkin for? - I brought it for Tommy. I figured
carving a Jack-O-Lantern would keep him occupied.
我們應該弄個精彩的女童軍遊戲
I always said you'd make a fabulous girl scout.
謝謝
老實說，今晚我都要演女童軍
Thanks. - And for that matter,
I might as well be a girl scout myself tonight.
我計劃做爆米花，然後看《痴呆醫生》
I plan on making popcorn
and watching Doctor Demensia.
六個小時的恐怖電影，小林西肯定會嚇一大跳
Six straight hours of horror movies.
Little Lindsey Wallace won't know what hit her.
我爸
My dad!
快丟掉
Get rid of this.
勞莉，別咳了，你怎麼回事？
Laurie, stop caughing. What's the matter with you?
自然一點，他在那裡
Just be natural. There he is. Just be natural, Laurie.
安妮，勞莉
Hi, Annie, Laurie...
嗨，爸爸
Hi, Dad.
什麼事？ 什麼？
What happened?  What? What happened?
有人硬闖進了那間倉庫 可能是小孩
Somebody broke into the hardware store. Probably kids.
你把任何事都怪在小孩頭上
You blame everything on kids.
他們拿走了一些萬聖節面具，一條繩子，還有幾把小刀
要不然你認為是誰做的？
What all they took was some Halloween masks, a rope
and a couple of knives. Who do you think it was?
很難跟這位偏執的老爸溝通
It's hard growing up with a cynical father.
你要遲到了吧？
什麼？
Aren't you gonna be late ...
- Huh?
我說你要遲到了
他又在吼了
I said aren't you gonna be late.
- He shouts too.
再見！孩子們
Bye girls.
再見！爸爸
再見
Bye dad.
- Bye.
警長
Sheriff.
打擾了，我是盧米斯，山姆盧米斯醫生
Pardon me, I'm a Loomis. Dr. Sam Loomis.
李布蘭提
- 如果可以，我想和你說幾句
Lee Brackett.
- I, I'd like to have a word with you if I could.
好，稍等幾分鐘，我得拿那個
這事很重要
Ah, maybe a few minutes. I gotta take that
- It's just important.
等十分鐘
我在這裡等
Ten minutes.
- I'll be here.
你怎麼了？
What's the matter with you?
我想他知道了，他聞得出來
I think he knew. I'm sure he could smell it.
他聞不出來的
他一定聞出來了
No, he didn't.
- He did.
看到他的表情了嗎？
See the look on his face?
他一向都是那種表情
He always looks like that.
你明晚舞會穿什麼衣服？
What  you gonna wear on dance tommorow night?
我沒想到你會問這問題，勞莉
I didn't know you thought about things like that, Laurie.
要知道你可以去請別人
- 不，我不行
You know you could ask somebody.
- No, I couldn't.
你當然可以，你只要過去說
Sure you could.
All you have to do is go up to somebody and say ...
你想跳舞嗎？
You wanna go to the dance?
你可以，我不行
You could do that, I couldn't.
或者你去約迪克帕西特 他會來的
Or you could ask Dick Paxter.
He could go out with ya.
那我寧願約班催莫
I try to get out Ben Tramor.
班催莫？
Ben Tramor?
我就知道！
I knew it!
你一直這樣想，對吧，勞莉？
See, you do think about things like that, huh, Laurie?
閉嘴！ 他很帥
Shut up. He is cute.
班催莫！
Ben Tramor.
好
Ok.
再見
Bye.
不給糖就搗亂 不給糖就搗亂
Trick or treat, trick or treat:
give me something good to eat.
嗨 - 嗨，安妮，請進
- 今天怎麼樣？ - 還好，你呢？
Hi. - Hi Annie, come on in.
- How are you doing today? - Fine. How are you?
準備幾點睡？
九點
What time are you in your bed?
I'm being in bed by nine, ok.
玩得開心，親愛的
- 要乖啊
Have a good night, dear.
- Be a good girl.
再見！
Bye bye.
- Here.
有人住這裡嗎？
- 沒有，自從1963年發生那事後就沒人住了
Anybody lives here?
- No, not since 1963 when that happened.
這裡的人都認為這是棟凶宅，不乾淨
- 我也會這麼想的
Every kid in Haddonfield thinks this place is haunted.
- They may be right.
看！ 什麼？
Look. What?
那是什麼？
What is that?
一隻狗
It's a dog.
還有熱度
Still warm.
他一定餓極了
He got hungry.
他已經瘋了
Could have been a skunk.
可能是
Could have.
正常人不會這樣
A man wouldn't do that ...
他不是正常人
This is not a man.
這就是案發現場
It happened in here.
她當時坐在這裡
She was sitting right here ...
他可能從這個窗戶看到她
He could have seen her thru this window.
站在草坪上
Standing on the lawn ...
能看到這裡
He could have seen in side.
你一定以為我是
You must think of me ...
一個精神不正常的醫生
the very sinister doctor.
這是我的醫師執照
I do have a permit.
我覺得你好像很害怕
Seems to me you're just plain scared.
是的
Yes.
是的，我
Yeah, I'm a...
我在15年前見他時
我當時認為他己沒救
I met him ... fifteen years ago.
I was told there was nothing left.
沒有知覺，無法溝通
對生命和死亡沒有概念
No reason ... nowhere conscience, no understanding
in even the most rudimentary sense, of life or death of ...
沒有分出善惡的能力
good or evil, right or wrong.
我看到了這個
I met this ...
6歲小孩的那張
six year-old child with his ...
空洞，蒼白，沒有表情的臉
blank, pale, emotionless face, and ...
和那雙來自黑暗的
the blackest eyes ...
魔鬼般的眼睛
the Devil's eyes.
我花了八年的時間想和他溝通
I spent eight years trying to reach him ...
之後七年把他完全拘禁 因為我知道
and then another seven trying to keep him locked up,
because I realized that
這個男孩眼睛的後面是無窮無盡的
what was living behind that boy's eyes
was purely and simply...
邪惡
... evil.
我們怎麼辦？
What do we do?
他今晚曾來過
He's been here once tonight ...
我想他會回來
I think he'll come back.
我在這裡等他
I'm gonna wait for him.
我認為應該通知廣播和電視台
- 不
I still think I should notify the radio and television.
- No.
這樣人們會恐慌，會到處找他，如此恐怕會打草驚蛇
If you do that, they'll see him on every street corner, they
look for him on every house. Just tell your men to keep their ...
還是叫你的人保守機密，嚴密監視他的出沒
mouth shut and their eyes open.
一小時後我再回來看看
I'll check back in an hour.
亞瑟現在哭的很傷心
... oh now, cried Arthur.
“讓每個人都加入這場混戰！”
'Let no one pass this way without a fight!'
“就這樣”騎士大膽
'That's so,' said the knight
而又傲慢的說
in a bold and haughty manner.
我不喜歡那個故事
我以為亞瑟王是你最喜歡的
I don't like that story.
- I thought king Arthur was your favorite.
不再是了
Not anymore.
為什麼都藏在底下？
Why do you keep them under there?
媽媽不讓我留著
Mom doesn't like me to have them.
雷射超人
'Laser Man' ...
中子人，我知道為什麼了
'Neutron Man' ... I can understand why.
飛天超人
'Tarantula Man' ...
勞莉
Laurie ...
什麼是惡魔人？
what's the Boogeyman?
道爾公館
Doyle residence.
是我
嗨，安妮，你在做什麼？
It's me ...
- Hi Annie, what are you doing?
做爆米花
Making popcorn ...
取樂
Having fun ...
你一定也是一樣
Never mind, I'm sure you are.
我有一個好消息告訴你
I have big, big news for you ...
你等一下
Hold on a minute.
嗨 李斯特
Hi Lester...
我要被這隻惡犬咬得稀巴爛了
I'm about to be ripped apart by the family dog.
林西，快把這隻狗從廚房帶走
Lindsey ... get this dog out of the kitchen right now.
我恨那隻狗
是世界上它唯一不喜歡的人
I hate that dog ...
I'm the only person in the world he doesn't like.
是什麼大好消息？
So, what is this big, big news?
如果我說你會參加明晚的舞會 你信不信？
What would you say if I told you that you were going
to the Homecoming Dance tomorrow night?
我會說你拔錯電話號碼了
I would probably say you've got the wrong number.
好吧
Well ...
我剛才打電話給班催莫 告訴他你覺得他很有吸引力
I just talked with Ben Tramer and he got real excited
when I told him how attracted you were to him.
噢，安妮
Oh, Annie ...
噢，不要，你不會真說了吧
Oh, you didn't. Please tell me you didn't.
你怎麼能這樣做？
How could you do that?
你怎麼打電話告訴他這些？
I mean how you just call him.
What do you mean it's easy?
我簡直不敢相信
I can't believe this.
我實在不應該把任何事都告訴你
I can't tell you anything.
你一定是在騙我的
Please tell me you didn't.
肯定是騙我的
Oh, you didn't.
好尷尬，我沒辦法見他了
勞莉，惡魔人在外面
Laurie ... - I'm so embarrassed, I couldn't even face him.
- Boogeyman is outside.
勞莉，就在那裡
等一下
Laurie ... out there.
- Hold on.
勞莉，惡魔人在外面，快看！
Laurie, the boogeyman is outside. Look!
湯米，外面沒有人
Tommy, there is nobody outside.
去看電視
Go watch TV.
剛才是湯米
It's just Tommy.
噢，安妮
Oh, please, Annie ...
你為什麼這樣做
You could do that.
很簡單，他喜歡你，你也喜歡他
你們需要的是一點推力
Look it's simple. You like him, he likes you.
All you need is a little push.
老實說，和他約會只會對你有好處
It won't hurt you to go out with him, for God's sake.
他媽的
Shit!
不不！我把衣服弄濕了
我一會再打給你
No, no, I just made a mess on myself.
I gotta call you back.
噢，倒霉！
Oh, yuck!
林西
Lindsey ...
我需要一件衣服
I need a robe.
林西
Lindsey ...
那狗又再叫了 我這樣會神經緊張的
Lester's barking again and getting on my nerves again.
沒事了
Never mind ...
他一定在約會
I guess he found a hot date.
什麼時候做傑克燈籠？
先把電影看完
What about the Jack-O-Lantern?
- After the movie.
那我的故事書呢？
做完傑克燈籠再說
What about the rest of my comic books?
- After the Jack-O-Lantern.
那惡魔人呢？
What about the boogeyman?
這東西不存在
There is no such thing.
瑞其說他今晚會來抓我
Richie said he was coming after me tonight.
瑞其說什麼你都信嗎？
Do you believe everything that Richie tells you?
不是
No.
湯米，萬聖節的夜晚，大家都想愚弄人
Tommy, Halloween night ...
it's when people play tricks on each other.
相信我，瑞其只是想嚇嚇你
It's all make believe.
I think Richie was just trying to scare you.
我看到惡魔人了 他就在外面
I saw the boogeyman. I saw him outside.
外面沒有人
There was nobody outside.
有
那他長什麼樣子？
There was.
- What did he look like?
長得像惡魔！
The boogyeman!
這麼說沒有任何意義
We're not getting anywhere.
好吧
All right.
惡魔人只在萬聖節晚上出現，對吧？
The boogyeman can only come out
on Halloween night, right?
對
Right.
那好，我整晚都在這裡，這樣你就不會害怕了吧
Welll, I'm here tonight.
I'm not about to let anything happen to you.
你保證？
Promise?
我保證
Promise.
我們現在做傑克燈籠好嗎？
Can we make the Jack-O-Lantern now?
走
Let's go.
太棒了！
Hmm, terrific.
哈囉？
Hello?
誰在那裡？
Who's there?
保羅，這又是你的惡作劇對吧？
Paul, is this one of your cheap pranks?
也許不是
Guess not.
今晚應該不會有人捉弄我
No tricks for Annie tonight.
林西
Lindsey!
林西，到這邊來！
Lindsey, come out here!
林西，我被反鎖在洗衣間了！開不了門！
Lindsey, I'm in the laundry room! The door wouldn't open!
大家分頭找
Spread out everybody.
我們要弄清楚這個東西長什麼樣
We gonna try to figure out the shape of this thing.
我的天
Holly cat.
嘿
對了
Hey.
- Yeah.
幾近完美 怎麼了？
Almost perfect.
What's wrong?
我們終於找到一個了 我們發現了源頭
We finally got one.
- We found a plain sourcer.
林西，快去接電話，是保羅打來的
Oh, Lindsey, get the phone, it's Paul.
林西！
Lindsey!
Lindseeey!
不，沒有響應 - 博士，這些手指頭使從哪來的？
No, no answer. - Doctor, where are those fingers from?
我不清楚，史考特先生
哈囉？
I don't know, Mr. Scott.
Hallo?
嗨，林西，我是保羅，安妮在嗎？
Hi Lindsey, this is Paul. Is Annie there?
在，她在
Yes, she is.
幫我找她，好不好？
Get her for me, will ya?
她在洗衣服
She's washing her clothes.
告訴她我來過電話，好嗎？
Look, just tell her it's me, ok?
好
Ok.
安妮！保羅來電話了
Annie, Paul called!
你怎麼掛在那裡？
我知道
You locked yourself there.
- I know.
拉我一把，我被卡住了
Pull my foot. I'm stuck!
好了，不許跟別人提這件事
Now promise me you won't tell anybody about this.
她剛剛被窗給卡住了，現在回來了
She got stuck in a window. She'll be right here.
哈囉！
嗨，安妮
Hello?
Hi Annie.
噢，嗨，保羅
被卡住了，是真的嗎？
Oh, hi Paul.
Stuck, huh?
好了，不要說了，誰都會
沒錯，被窗卡住了
All right, cut it out. It can happen to anyone.
Sure ... stuck in the widow.
沒錯，我也看見你卡在很多地方啊
Yeah, but I've seen you stuck in plenty of other positions!
我爸媽出去了
My parents are gone.
太好了，什麼時候出去的
Oh that's fabulous. When did they leave?
半小時前
這太好了
About half ago
- Oh, utterly fantastic.
你為什麼不走路過來？
So why don't you just walk over?
你來接我
現在不行，我在洗衣服
You coming pick me up.
- Well, I can't come now. My clothes are in the wash.
那你沒穿
住口，混蛋，我穿衣服了，你滿腦子淨想那些
Oh shut up jerk. Can't, I've got a shirt on.
That's all you ever think about.
我覺得你才滿腦子想那些
胡說，我想到很多事情
I think that's all you ever think about.
- That's not true, I think about lots of things.
為什麼我們不停止紙上談兵去實踐一下呢？
Now why don't we not stand here
talking about them and get down to doing them?
關好門，鎖緊窗戶，關掉燈
Lock your doors, bolt your window and turn off the lights.
別離開 一會你將看到奇蹟
我好怕
Don't go away ... cause here is a scene ...
- I'm scared.
那你為什麼要坐在這麼暗的地方呢？
Then why are you sitting here with half the lights off?
我不知道
走，去拿你的外套，我們去接保羅
I don't know.
- Well, come on get your coat.
We're going to pick up Paul.
我不想去
I don't want to.
林西，我以為我們互相了解對方
我想待在這看電影
Look, Lindsey, I thought we understood each other...
- I want to stay here and watch this.
好，我帶你去湯米道爾家和他一起看電視，你不好？
Okay, if I can fix it so you can watch TV
with Tommy Doyle, would you like that?
好呀！
那跟我走吧
Yes.
- Well, come with me.
快點！
Come on! Hurry up.
That strange that has to short it out.
嗨，湯米
Hi Tommy.
嗨
Hi.
請進，我們正在做傑克燈籠
但是我想看電視
Come on in. We're making a Jack-O-Lantern.
- You know I wanna watch TV.
安妮，來這邊
Annie, come in here.
...now the horrifying conclusion ...
... to ... the them.
噢，真迷人！
Oh, fancy.
今晚不是屬於我的
This has not been my night.
我不小心把牛奶潑在身上，衣服正在洗，我還卡在了窗上
我希望你能打電話給班，告訴他你只是在開玩笑
I spilled butter all over. My cloths are in the wash.I got stuck in a window.
I'd like you call Ben Tramer and tell him you're just fooling around.
不行 - 行的，你可以的
不行，他和麥克戈弗雷喝酒，很晚才回來
I can't. - Yes, you can. - No, he went drinking with
Mike Godfrey and he won't be back until late.
你明天自己打電話給他
YOU'LL have to call him ... tomorrow.
況且我正要去接保羅
Besides, I'm on my way to pick up Paul.
等一下
Wait a minute.
如果你幫我照顧小孩，我會考慮明早打電話給班催莫
If you watch her,
I'll CONSIDER talking to Ben Tramer in the morning.
成交
Deal.
我以為保羅被禁足了
沒錯，這小子想辦法溜出來了
I thought Paul was grounded.
- He was. Old jerko found a way to sneak out.
我一小時後再打電話給你，好吧？
- 好
Listen, I'll call you in an hour or so, ok?
- Yeah.
再見！
Bye.
女童軍的性格又表露無遺了
The old girl scout comes through again.
* 今夜，保羅，我什麼都給你 *
* My Paul ... I give you all *
* 沒有鎖匙 但我的保羅，請你 *
* No keys, but pleeease ... *
*my Paul *
* 噢，保羅 *
* 我不會再晚了 *
* Oh, Paul ... *
*I can no longer stall... *
* 噢，保羅，噢，保羅 *
* 我不會再晚了 *
* Oh Paul. Oh Paul ...*
*I can no longer stall... *
* 親愛的保羅 *
* Dearly Paul ... *
* 我的保羅 *
* my Paul *
注意！
Attention ...
船長和其他人員準備器械
Captain and crew standby reverse polarity.
地點第8檢查站，在那裡降落
Standard class A security will be maintained upon landing.
直到所有人員出   我們就接收
And until further notice all land in and hold on.
完畢
That is all.
進入重力區域
Artificial gravity are ...
主要出入口封閉
ad lock cut primary coarse.
出入口都封閉了，長官
Primary stature.
林西
Lindsey ...
Lindseyyy ....
你在哪裡？
Where are you?
我看到惡魔人了！他在外面！惡魔人在外面！
- 怎麼了？
There is the boogeyman! He is outside! Look, there is the boogeyman outside!
- What's wrong?
我看到惡魔人！真的 - 湯米，別吵了
在林西家那邊！- 你會把林西嚇哭的
I saw the boogeyman! I know that - Oh, Tommy stop it!
- But at Lindsey's! - You're scaring Lindsey.
他在那裡！
湯米，夠了！外面沒有人！
He's over there!
- Tommy, stop it! There is nobody out there!
沒有惡魔人，如果你還吵
我就把電視關掉，拉你去睡覺
There's no boogeyman. And if you don't stop all this
I'll have to turn off the TV and send you to bed.
沒人相信我
我相信你，湯米
Nobody believes me.
- I believe you, Tommy.
我才不怕
I'm not afraid.
吹牛
Bull.
我不怕
那就進去吧！
I'm not.
- Then go in.
膽小鬼
Chicken.
別發抖，進去吧！郎尼
Go ahead, Lonnie.
進去呀！
Go in!
嘿！
Hey!
嘿，郎尼
Hey, Lonnie ...
你最好別接近那裡
Get your ass away from there ...
老天
Jesus.
你還好吧？
Are you all right here?
還好
Yeah.
除了孩子們的嘻斗之外
似乎沒發生任何事
Well, nothing's going on except kids playing pranks,
trick or treating, partying, getting high.
我覺得你太小提大作了
I have the feeling you're way off on this.
你這樣想是不對的
但目前為止尚未證明我是錯的
You have the wrong feeling.
- You're not doing very much to prove me wrong.
你還需要證明嗎？
What more do you need?
當然，要讓我整夜都藏在這樹叢的後面
靠說這些荒誕的東西還不夠
Well, it's going to take more than fancy talk
to keep me up all night crawling around these bushes.
我觀察他15年了
I, I, I watched him for fifteen years ...
他坐在房間裡，呆看著牆壁，不只是看著
sitting in a room, staring at a wall, not seeing the wall ...
甚至要看穿牆壁
looking past the wall
如果你有這耐心
looking at ... THIS NIGHT inhumanly patient.
等一個神密，無聲的危險人物
waiting for some secret, silent alarm ...
等待他的出現
to trigger him off.
死亡己逼近你這個小鎮，警長
Death has come to your little town, sheriff.
你要嘛不理不睬，要嘛幫我阻止他
You can either ignore it or you can help me to stop it.
你又在說怪誕的事
More fancy talk.
大夫，你了解哈登菲爾德鎮嗎？
Doctor, do you know what Haddonfield is?
家人
Families ...
孩子們，他們都成群結隊地在街道上上下下
Children ... all lined up in rows,
up and down these streets.
而你卻告訴我他們可能會有危險
You're telling me they're lined up for a slaughterhouse.
很有可能
They could be.
好，今晚我和你待在這裡
All right, I'll stay with you out tonight ...
就當作你說的不假
just on the chance that you're right.
就算你說的都是事實
And if you are right ...
你也要為他的逃跑負責
damn you for letting him go.
好，我告訴你，我們先進去，好吧？
然後我們談幾句話
So we gonna first, we'll go inside, right?
Then we just talk a little.
當安妮把林西支走時，我們就上樓到左邊第一個房間 了解了嗎？
Then Annie will distract Lindsey, that's when we'll
go upstairs to the first bedroom on the left. You got it?
首先我撕掉你的衣服
First I rip your clothes off ...
不要撕我的胸衣，那很貴的，白痴
然後你撕掉我的衣服
Don't rip, my blouse is expensive, idiot.
- Then you rip my clothes off...
然後我們把林西的衣服也撕掉
耶！我覺得我全明白了！
then we rip Lyndsey's cloth off. Yeah, I think I got it.
你全明白了
Totally.
巴伯，放我下來
Bob ... put me down.
放我下來，別鬧了
Put me down. This is totally silly.
放我下來
Put me down.
怎麼這麼暗
是呀！
Hey, it's totally dark.
- Yeah.
安妮！
Annie!
安妮，我們來了
他們去哪了？
Annie, we're here!
- I wonder where they went.
安妮可能帶林西出去了
Annie probably took Lindsey out or something.
找找看有沒有留字條
Hey, let's look for a note.
別找了
Let's not.
他會抓到你的
He's gonna get you ...
不，他抓不到
嘿，沒有誰要抓任何人 不要嚇人
No, he's not. - Hey, nobody's getting anybody.
Stop scaring each other.
今夜每個人都各得其所
Everybody's having good time tonight.
好，小鬼，下來要玩什麼？
All right, guys, what's next?
我們再多做點爆米花吧
不，已經夠多了 要不一起把電影看完吧？
Let's make more popcorn. - No, we had enough.
Why don't we watch the rest of the movie?
好
Yeah.
好了， 把它放回去
All right, put it back on.
道爾公館
Doyle house.
嗨，勞莉，怎麼樣了
Hi Laurie ... what's up?
我今晚才剛剛坐下來
I'm just setting down for the first time tonight.
嘿，安妮在你那裡嗎？
Hey ... is Annie around?
不在，她現在應該回去了
No, I thought she'd be home by now.
她說要去接保羅
她根本不在這裡
She went to pick up Paul.
- Well, she's totally not here.
她大概去別地方了
She's probably stopped off some place.
她回去時讓她給我打個電話
林西在我這邊，我要知道何時叫她去睡覺
Have her call me when she gets home.
I've got Lyndsey here and I want to know
what time to put her to bed.
好，待會見
祝你愉快
Okay. Later.
- Have a good time.
我們一定會很愉快的
We definetely will.
再見！
Bye.
林西晚上不會回來了
那太好了
Lindsey is gone for the night.
- Hey, now that's wonderful.
媽的！又來了
Oh, shit! Not again.
真受不了，這電話老是響個不停
I can't help it. The phone keeps ringing.
噢，我沒辦法讓你保持興奮，對嗎？
還是快接這破電話吧！
Oh, I can't keep you interested, huh?
- Just answer that damn phone.
不能接 要是華萊士夫婦打回來的怎麼辦？
I can't. What if it's the Wallaces?
接了安妮可就麻煩了
We'd get Annie in trouble now.
我們把話筒拿起來
Just take it off the hook.
太棒了！
Fantastic.
太美了
是呀！
Totally.
- Yeah.
滿足了嗎？
Is that all you can say?
是的
Yeah.
去拿瓶酒給我
應該你去拿給我
Go get me a beer.
- I thought you were gonna get me one.
快去
Yeaah.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
不要把衣服穿上
Don't get dressed.
安妮？
Annie?
保羅？
Paul?
林西你這王八蛋
Lynda, you asshole!
好了！琳達
Ok, Lynda.
出來吧！
Come on out.
我的酒呢？
Well, did you get my beer?
可愛，巴伯，你很可愛
Cute, Bob. Real cute.
看到你喜歡的東西了嗎？
See anything you like?
怎麼了？巴伯，你能脫掉那套衣服嗎？
What's the matter? Can I get your ghost, Bob?
好了，別鬧了，我的啤酒呢？
All right, all right. Come on, where is my beer?
你回答我好不好？
Ok, ain't answer me?
好，你別回答了
Ok, don't answer me?
你真奇怪！我要打電話給勞莉
Oh, you're weird!
- I'm gonna call Laurie.
我要打電話給勞莉
我要知道保羅和安妮去哪裡了
Well, I'm gonna call Laurie.
I wanna know where Annie and Paul are.
這就不好玩了哦
This is going nowhere.
終於打來了
Finally.
哈囉！
Hello.
哈囉？
Hello?
好了，安妮，上次是在吃東西
這次變成尖叫了？
All right, Annie. First I get your famous chewing,
now I get your famous squealing?
安妮，你沒事吧？
Annie, you all right?
你是不是又在開玩笑？
Are you fooling around again?
如果又在開玩笑，我會殺了你
I'll kill you if this is a joke.
安妮？
Annie?
好好睡，孩子們
Sleep tight, kids.
保羅？
Paul?
琳達？
Lynda?
安妮？
Annie?
琳達？
Lynda?
巴伯？
Bob?
好了，安妮
All right, Annie ...
好了，你們，玩笑結束了
All right, meatheads. The joke's over.
快出來，安妮
Come on, Annie.
玩夠了
It's enough.
已經不好玩了，別鬧了
This is most definitely stopping funny.
Now cut it out!
你會後悔的
You'll be sorry.
不要
No.
救命！
Help!
快來人呀！
Somebody help me, please!
來人呀！
Somebody help!
噢，上帝，救我！
Oh, God, help me!
快！
Please!
快救我！
Please, help me!
救命！
Heeeelp!
噢，上帝，救我，快點！
Oh, God, help me, please!
哈囉！
Hello!
Helloo!
有人嗎？
Hello?
快來救我！
Helloo, help me!
能救救我嗎？
Will you please help me?
快！
Please!
你們聽到沒有？
Can't you hear me?!
天啊！
Oh,God ...
快救我！
Help me, please!
鎖匙呢？
The keys!
鎖匙！
Oh, the keys!
湯米！
Tommyy!
湯米，是我！
Tommy, it's mee!
湯米！
Tommyy!
誰啊？
湯米，快開門，是我！
Who is it?
- Tommy, open up, it's mee!
湯米，快！
Tommy please!
湯米，快點！
Tommy, hurry up!
湯米，求你了！
Tommy please!
快點！湯米，求求你快點！
Hurry up! Tommy please!
湯米快上樓 - 出了什麼事，勞莉？
湯米快回樓上去，和林西一起，關好門
Tommy, go upstairs. - What is it, Laurie?
- Tommy go back upstairs,
grab the Lindsey and lock the door.
我好怕！- 照我說的做！快去！
是惡魔人來了，是嗎？- 快點！
I'm scared!- Do what I say! Now!
- It's the boogeyman, isn't it? - Hurry!
噢，不要！
Oh, no ...
求求你，不要
Please, stop.
求求你
Please ...
你去哪了？我剛從麥爾家回來
我找到那部車了，他在這裡
Where were you? I went to the Meyers house.
- I found the car. He is here!
哪裡？- 在三個街區之內
你回去在麥爾家附近看看，我在這裡找
Where? - He's three blocks down.
You go around back off the houses, I'll watch the front.
快呀！
Go on!
湯米！林西
Tommy ... Lyndsey ...
寶貝
Babies ...
我們必須走一段路
We're gonna take a little walk.
是惡魔人嗎？
Was it the boogeyman?
- 我好怕
不用怕了
-I'm scared.
-There's nothing to be scared of.
真的嗎？
Are you sure?
為什麼？
How?
我殺了他
I killed him.
你殺不死惡魔人的
You can't kill the boogeyman.
快進去，湯米，把門鎖好
Get in there! Come on, Tommy! Now, lock the door!
湯米
Tommy ...
把門打開
Unlock the door.
過來
Come here.
聽著
Now just listen to me ...
你們下樓
I want you to go down the stairs ...
把前門鎖好
and out the front door.
沿著街去瑪肯姬家
And I want you to go down the street
to the Mackenzies' house ...
然後叫他們報警
I want you to tell them to call the police.
叫警察來這裡
And tell them to send them over here.
勞莉
快去，聽到了嗎？
Laurie ...
- Now, do you understand me?
知道了
快，照我說的做
Yes. - Go. Do as I say.
找人來幫忙！
Get help!
快點！
Come on!
那是惡魔人嗎？
Was that the boogeyman?
老實說
As a matter of fact ...
他就是
it was.
特效 KYSDM
時間軸 KYSDM
翻譯 SIMWONG
月光光心慌慌
時間軸 KYSDM
特效 KYSDM